The Cambiaso family
La familia Cambiaso
had maintained
mantuvo
close ties with Genoa
estrechos vínculos con Génova
their city of origin
su ciudad de origen
Giovanni Battista and his brother Luigi
Giovanni Battista y su hermano Luigi
returned several times
volvieron varias veces
to Genoa, and on one of these occasions
a Génova, y en una de esas ocasiones
they brought with them and donated to the mayor
llevaron consigo y donaron al alcalde
a small vial
un pequeño frasco
containing a portion
que contenía una porción
of what was believed to be
de lo que se suponía que eran
the ashes of Christopher Columbus
las cenizas de Cristóbal Colón
found in the cathedral of Santo Domingo
halladas en la catedral de Santo Domingo
in a lecture the Cambiaso brothers
en una conferencia que los Cambiaso
gave at the local Historical Society
dieron en la Sociedad de Historia Patria local
they suggested to the mayor of Genoa
sugirieron al alcalde de Génova
that the city should organize
organizar en la ciudad
the celebrations for the fourth centenary
las celebraciones por el cuarto centenario
of the discovery of America
del descubrimiento de América
and in fact, in 1892
y, de hecho, en 1892
Genoa would celebrate
Génova celebró
with a large Italo-American exposition
con una gran exposición italoamericana
the discovery of America
el descubrimiento de América
we can assume that the Cambiaso family
podemos suponer que los Cambiaso
intended to exhibit
quisieron exhibir
the two cemíes in Genoa on that occasion
en aquella ocasión los dos cemíes en Génova
but we have
pero no tenemos
no documentation to support this hypothesis
documentación que respalde esta hipótesis